**New: Smart Animate** — Bring movement to your prototypes. [Learn more](https://www.sketch.com/blog/smart-animate/)

[**New: Smart Animate** — Bring movement to your prototypes. Learn more](https://www.sketch.com/blog/smart-animate/)

Menu

* Product

    * More

    What’s New

* Learn

    * Courses

* Help

icon-close

* * Product
* * Learn
* * Help

Contents

### Contents

Cancel

### Contents

Privacy Statement
=================

Version 26 April 2023
---------------------

This Privacy Statement informs you about the type of personal data we collect from you, and we process them through our website ([www.sketch.com](https://www.sketch.com/home/)), Sketch Platform (Mac app, Web app, and Sketch iOS app, as applicable) as these terms are defined and described in our [Terms of Service](https://www.sketch.com/tos/).

Personal information refers to any information that can be used to distinguish one individual from another. In the General Data Protection Regulation (”GDPR”) personal data is defined as any information relating to an identified or identifiable natural person (‘data subject’).

### Who we are

We are the Dutch company, Sketch B.V. (“we” or “us”), with a place of business at Flight Forum 40, Ground floor, 5657 DB Eindhoven, the Netherlands, with a chamber of commerce registration number 60360461 and VAT number NL8538.75.273.B01.

We are the controller responsible for the processing of personal data through our website and Sketch Platform.

### What personal data do you collect from me?

Depending on how you use our services, we may collect and process the following types of personal data.

#### Information you provide us

We collect information you provide when you:

* create a Sketch account
* use the Sketch Platform
* contact us
* fill-in any forms on our website
* show interest in receiving any other information from us
* take part in online discussions or forums
* interact with us on social media
* participate in research activities

In particular, we will process and/or collect the following information:

1. Contact & communication details (such as name, address, email, phone numbers, language spoken);
2. Account details (such as email address, password, profile picture/avatar, name alias, username, license key if applicable);
3. Payment information ( such as the full name of cc’s owner, last four digits of credit card, credit card expiration date, type of credit card, bank entity issuing the credit card, and country of origin);
4. Records of our discussions when you contact us for support
5. Proof of student status (e.g. a student card that may include your date of birth)

We may collect other types of personal data if required under applicable law or if this is necessary for the purposes listed in this Privacy Statement.

#### Information collected automatically

We collect certain information automatically when, and depending on how, you use Sketch Platform.

When you use our **Web app**, this information may include:

* your Internet protocol (IP) address
* country
* details about your browser
* device information (e.g. computer name)
* timestamps

When you use our **Mac app**, this information may include:

* your Internet protocol (IP) address
* device information (computer name, model, GPU & CPU type, UDID which is your Mac Unique ID, macOS Version)
* timestamps
* license identifier

When you use our **Sketch** **iOS app**, this information may include:

* your Internet protocol (IP) address
* device information (e.g. device name)
* timestamps

#### Cookies & similar technologies

We may store cookies on your device if necessary for the smooth operation of our website and web application, including for being able to log in.

We may also use Analytics, Advertising and Functionality cookies, **but only after you have provided your consent to any of these**.

Please refer to our [Cookie Policy](https://www.sketch.com/cookie-policy/) for more information.

#### Information from other sources

If you use Sketch Platform on behalf of, or in collaboration with, a Company that is a Sketch customer (e.g., your employer, a reseller, an agent, a sales representative or other), that company may provide us with information about you so that we can provision your account.

### Legal basis for processing

When we process personal data, we rely on the following legal bases:

* **Contractual obligation** — We process personal data because this is necessary for the performance of the contract between you and us. For example, we cannot create an account for you, if you choose not to share your personal data with us.
    
* **Legal obligation** — There may be cases when we have a legal responsibility to process your personal data in order to comply with our legal obligations.
    
* **Legitimate interest** — Our legitimate interests are our commercial company interests (e.g. to improve our products and services), our interest to prevent fraud, and our interest to report possible criminal acts or threats to competent authorities. We rely on this reason only when reasonable, and when balanced against your human rights and freedoms.
    
* **Consent** — When you have given us explicit consent to process your personal data for a specific purpose.

### How we may use personal data

The table below summarises the ways in which we may use your personal data.

| What we use your personal data for | Our legal basis for using your personal data |
| --- | --- |
| **Providing Sketch Platform**  <br>When you sign-up and use our platform, we use your personal data to:  <br>\- create and manage an account for you on Sketch Platform;  <br>\- processing payment card and/or other financial information | Keeping to contracts and agreements between you and us  <br>\- Legitimate interests (we need to be efficient about how we meet our obligations and we want to provide you with good products and services)  <br>\- Legal obligations |
| **Providing technical or other support**  <br>We may record and monitor any communications between you and us, to maintain appropriate records, check your instructions, analyse, assess and improve our services, and for training and quality control purposes. | Keeping to contracts and agreements between you and us  <br>\- Legitimate interests (we need to be efficient about how we meet our obligations, and we want to provide you with good products and services) |
| **Communicate with you regarding platform issues or incidents** | Keeping to contracts and agreements between you and us  <br>\- Legal obligations (e.g. Data Protection laws) |
| **Communicate with you regarding important product updates, enhancements and insides, or to send you our newsletter** | Legitimate interests (to keep customers informed and to be efficient about how we meet our contractual duties).  <br>You will have the choice to opt-out from any such marketing communication.  <br>\- Consent (where we’re legally required to get your consent to send you direct marketing about our product). |
| **To analyse how our website and platform are used, such as which pages are visited and what features are used** | Legitimate interests (to understand how customers use our products so we can improve the products we currently provide) |
| **To verify compliance with applicable legal requirements and our policies** | Legal obligations |

### How we may share your personal data

We may share your personal data on a need-to-know basis with the following categories of third parties:

1. Our service providers; used in the provision of our products and services, e.g.
    
    * IT and data hosting services
    * Payment service providers
    * Communication service providers
    
    Here you can find the list of our [List of Subprocessors](https://www.sketch.com/subprocessors/).
    
2. Competent authorities or other third parties, if required by law or reasonably necessary, to protect the rights, property and safety of ourselves or others.

We reserve the right to transfer personal data about you in the event that we sell or transfer all or a portion of our business or assets in accordance with applicable law. Should such a sale or transfer occur, we will use reasonable efforts to direct the transferee to use the data you have provided to us in a manner that is consistent with this Privacy Statement. Following such a sale or transfer, you may contact the entity to which we transferred your data with any inquiries concerning the processing of that data.

**We do not sell, rent or trade your personal data.**

### How long do we retain personal data?

We retain personal data for as long as necessary to fulfil the purposes for which we collect or receive the personal data, except if required otherwise by applicable law.

Typically, we will retain most of the personal data for the duration of your use of the website and Sketch Platform until your account has expired, or has been deactivated, unless a longer applicable statutory retention period applies.

### Data transfers outside the EEA

We may transfer the personal data we obtain to third parties in countries outside the European Economic Area (EEA). In particular, personal data may be transferred to the United States. When we transfer your personal data outside the EEA, we will protect your personal data as described in this Privacy Statement and in accordance with applicable law, such as by entering into the European Commission’s [Standard Contractual Clauses](https://ec.europa.eu/info/law/law-topic/data-protection/international-dimension-data-protection/standard-contractual-clauses-scc_en) for the transfer of personal data to a processor located outside of the EEA.

### How we protect personal data

We maintain appropriate technical and organizational security safeguards designed to protect your personal data against accidental, unlawful or unauthorized destruction, loss, alteration, access, disclosure or use.

We will notify you of any data breach that is likely to have unfavourable consequences for your privacy in accordance with applicable law.

### Your Rights

In relation to your personal data, you have the right to:

1. Be informed on how your data are being processed.
2. Access your personal data, including confirmation whether we are processing your personal information and obtaining a copy of your personal information.
3. Request a correction of your personal data if inaccurate.
4. Request a deletion of your personal data.
5. Request Restriction of or Object to our processing of your personal information
6. Request us to provide you with your data in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format which can be transmitted to another controller.

To exercise these rights, please get in touch with us using our contact details set out below. We may request to prove your identity and/or your age. We will respond to your request within the applicable statutory term.

### Updates to this Privacy Statement

We may update this Privacy Statement from time to time. Any change we make to our Privacy Statement in the future will be posted on this page and, if such change is material, will be also notified to you via email. Please check back frequently for any updates or changes to our Privacy Statement. All changes shall be effective from the date of publication, unless otherwise provided in the notification.

It is important that the personal data we hold about you is accurate and current. Please keep us informed if your personal data changes during your relationship with us.

### How to Contact Us

If you have any comments or inquiries about the information in this Privacy Statement, if you would like us to update your personal data, or to exercise your rights, please contact us by email at **[privacy@sketch.com](mailto:privacy@sketch.com)**

In addition, you always have the right to make a complaint at any time to a competent supervisory authority.

Never miss an update
--------------------

Get all the latest news, blog posts and product updates from Sketch, delivered directly to your inbox. We’ll rarely send more than one email a month.

Email  Sign up

 I agree to receive marketing emails from Sketch.

### Product

### Why Sketch

### Learn

### Help

### Company

© 2024 Sketch B.V.
